Pol Rosello

PERSONAL PROFILE

U.S. Citizen with experience in embedded systems and artificial intelligence. Born and raised in Barcelona, Spain; attended high school in the U.S., living in California, Ohio, and New York. Native fluency in English, Spanish and Catalan; intermediate fluency in German.

EDUCATION

Stanford University, School of Engineering, Stanford, CA (4.15 GPA) Master of Science in Computer Science

expected June 2017

Cornell University, College of Engineering, Ithaca, NY (3.90 GPA)

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering

May 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

May 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Flight Software Intern

July 2015 – September 2015

SpaceX, Hawthorne, CA

Developed a bare-metal, flash-based file system currently used in the bootloader of several MCUs on the Crew Dragon's International Space Station docking motor controllers.

Developed an FPGA-based testbench for remote, automated microcontroller tests.

Wrote SPI drivers for an MCU in one of Falcon 9's attitude control systems.

Undergraduate Researcher

January 2014 – December 2014

Batten Group, Cornell University

Writing and optimizing benchmark applications for a novel high-performance, energy-efficient parallel computing microarchitecture by mapping them to a research ISA. Contributions acknowledged in two 2014 IEEE MICRO papers.

Software Engineering Intern

June 2014 – August 2014

Cisco Systems, San Jose, CA

Worked within the Internet of Things Group on the Connected Grid Network Management System, used to deploy and manage ~10 million endpoint IP-based wireless networks for smart grids.

Developed suites in C# to automate the zero-touch deployment, tunnel provisioning, and firmware upgrades of field routers; automated testing of the front-end functionality of the product.

Teaching Assistant

August 2013 – December 2014

Cornell University

Held office hours and review sessions, graded student projects and exams for ECE 4750/CS 4420: Computer Architecture (Fall 2014), ECE 3140/CS 3420: Embedded Systems (Spring 2014) and CS 2110: Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structures (Fall 2013)

Research Assistant

October 2012 – May 2013

Molnar Group, Cornell University

Programmed an FPGA and designed a printed circuit board as a testing platform for a very low power, very low noise multi-electrode array (MEA) for electrophysiological neural recordings.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Coursework: Embedded Systems • Machine Learning • AI • Computer Vision • Neural Networks • Natural Language Understanding • Computer Architecture • Operating Systems • Design with Microcontrollers • Algorithms • Data Structures • Networks • Digital Logic • Signal Processing • Microelectronics • Functional Programming • Evolutionary Algorithms • Discrete Mathematics • Neuroscience

Technologies: C/C++ • Python/NumPy • Verilog • Lua/Torch • OpenCV • AWS • OCaml • PCB design • ASM • MATLAB

HONORS AND AWARDS

Cornell College of Engineering Jacobs Scholar

Dean's List every semester

International Baccalaureate Full Diploma Recipient and AP Scholar with Distinction

See polrosello.com for contact information and selected projects.